Eliot-Pearson Department of Child Development Records UA009
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Office files, 1902 -- 2000; 1933 -- 1967; UA009.010; 6.65 Linear Feet
  - Chairman's correspondence, C CEC teacher education division-survey, 1989; UA009.010.009.00055 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Chairman's correspondence, D-F, 1989; UA009.010.009.00056 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Chairman's correspondence, G-I, 1989 -- 1990; UA009.010.009.00057 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Chairman's correspondence, J-L, 1986 -- 1990; UA009.010.009.00058 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Chairman's correspondence, M-O, 1988 -- 1990; UA009.010.009.00059 (Box UA009 Shared 3)
  - Chairman's correspondence, P-R, 1987 -- 1990; UA009.010.010.00001 (Box 10)
  - Chairman's correspondence, S-U, 1987 -- 1990; UA009.010.010.00002 (Box 10)
  - Chairman's correspondence, V-Z, 1986 -- 1990; UA009.010.010.00003 (Box 10)
  - Chairmanship evaluation, 1988 -- 1990; UA009.010.010.00004 (Box 10)
  - Clancy, Loise, 1990; UA009.010.010.00006 (Box 10)
  - Commencement, 1960; UA009.010.010.00007 (Box 10)
  - Curriculum committee, 1992; UA009.010.010.00008 (Box 10)
  - Curriculum issues eg. special tops 143 vs ind. study 140, 1990; UA009.010.010.00009 (Box 10)
  - Dean Feinleib, 1984 -- 1990; UA009.010.010.00010 (Box 10)
  - Dean Frank Concord, 1986; UA009.010.010.00011 (Box 10)
  - Dean Robert Guertin, 1987 -- 1990; UA009.010.010.00012 (Box 10)
  - Dean Larry Ladd, 1988 -- 1989; UA009.010.010.00013 (Box 10)
  - Eliot, Abigail Adams [1 of 7], 1922 -- 1952; UA009.010.010.00014 (Box 10)
  - Eliot, Abigail Adams [2 of 7], 1942 -- 1978; UA009.010.010.00015 (Box 10)
  - Eliot, Abigail Adams [3 of 7], 1958 -- 1972; UA009.010.010.00016 (Box 10)
  - Eliot, Abigail Adams [4 of 7], 1957 -- 1969; UA009.010.010.00017 (Box 10)
  - Eliot, Abigail Adams [5 of 7], 1926 -- 1973; UA009.010.010.00018 (Box 10)
  - Eliot, Abigail Adams [6 of 7], 1971 -- 1993; UA009.010.010.00019 (Box 10)
  - Eliot, Abigail Adams [7 of 7], 1961 -- 1974; UA009.010.010.00020 (Box 10)
  - Equipment and space inventory, 1978 -- 1987; UA009.010.010.00021 (Box 10)
  - Evaluation of majors 1995 senior survey, 1995 -- 1996; UA009.010.010.00022 (Box 10)
  - Faculty and staff notices [1 of 3], 1988 -- 1990; UA009.010.010.00023 (Box 10)
  - Faculty and staff notices [2 of 3], 1987 -- 1988; UA009.010.010.00024 (Box 10)
  - Faculty and staff notices [3 of 3], 1988 -- 1989; UA009.010.010.00025 (Box 10)
  - Goodenough, Evelyn, 1958 -- 1960; UA009.010.010.00026 (Box 10)
  - Goodman, Mary Ellen, 1955 -- 1959; UA009.010.010.00027 (Box 10)
  - Grade inflation, 1989; UA009.010.010.00028 (Box 10)
  - Intra departmental memos [1 of 2], 1986 -- 1987; UA009.010.010.00029 (Box 10)
  - Intra departmental memos [2 of 2], 1983 -- 1985; UA009.010.010.00030 (Box 10)
  - Langdon, Grace, 1956 -- 1957; UA009.010.010.00031 (Box 10)
  - Meisels, Samuel J, 1955; UA009.010.010.00032 (Box 10)
  - Policies, 1987 -- 1991; UA009.010.010.00033 (Box 10)
  - Policies committee [1 of 2], 1986 -- 1987; UA009.010.010.00034 (Box 10)
  - Policies committee [2 of 2], 1988 -- 1989; UA009.010.010.00035 (Box 10)
  - Policies handbook, 1989 -- 1991; UA009.010.010.00036 (Box 10)
  - Policies handbook, 1989; UA009.010.010.00037 (Box 10)
  - Policies handbook (first edition), 1989 -- 1990; UA009.010.010.00038 (Box 10)
  - Policies handbook, faculty guideline revisions, 1989 -- 1990; UA009.010.010.00039 (Box 10)
  - President Jean Mayer, 1978 -- 1990; UA009.010.010.00040 (Box 10)
  - Publications, 1964 -- 1979; UA009.010.010.00041 (Box 10)
  - Senior questionnaires, 1990 -- 1991; UA009.010.010.00042 (Box 10)
    Completed by 1990-10-22.
  - Space assignments, 1986 -- 1988; UA009.010.010.00043 (Box 10)
  - Space and equipment inventories, 1973 -- 1985; UA009.010.010.00044 (Box 10)
  - Success stories, 1990 -- 1992; UA009.010.011.00001 (Box 11)
  - Tenure-promot, 1982 -- 1987; UA009.010.011.00002 (Box 11)
  - This Bud's for you/alcohol and the media, 1989; UA009.010.011.00003 (Box 11)
  - TEDCC info, 1989; UA009.010.011.00004 (Box 11)
  - V.P. Rotberg, 1987 -- 1990; UA009.010.011.00005 (Box 11)
  - Wyatt, Gertrude L., 1989; UA009.010.011.00006 (Box 11)
  - Activities and meetings, 1933 -- 1954; UA009.010.014.00001 (Box 14)
  - Agreements, 1964 -- 1965; UA009.010.014.00002 (Box 14)
  - Agreements with Tufts, 1955 -- 1960; UA009.010.014.00003 (Box 14)
  - Associated daycare services, 1939 -- 1953; UA009.010.014.00004 (Box 14)
  - Bibliography of books for children, 1970; UA009.010.014.00005 (Box 14)
  - By-laws, 1931 -- 1962; UA009.010.014.00006 (Box 14)
  - Cambridge Nursery School, 1922 -- 1929; UA009.010.014.00007 (Box 14)
  - Certificates of incorporation, 1902 -- 1962; UA009.010.014.00008 (Box 14)
  - Child care and World War II, 1941 -- 1943; UA009.010.014.00009 (Box 14)
  - Children's School, 1961 -- 1976; UA009.010.014.00010 (Box 14)
  - A Child's World (pamphlet and correspondence), 1938 -- 1942; UA009.010.014.00011 (Box 14)
  - College of Special Studies, meeting minutes, 1957 -- 1959; UA009.010.014.00012 (Box 14)
  - Commencement, 1955 -- 1961; UA009.010.014.00013 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1954 -- 1964; UA009.010.014.00014 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1964 -- 1975; UA009.010.014.00015 (Box 14)
  - Daycare standards, 1956 -- 1964; UA009.010.015.00001 (Box 15)
  - Directory of faculty and staff, 1955 -- 1956; UA009.010.015.00002 (Box 15)
  - Dormitory regulations, 1957; UA009.010.015.00003 (Box 15)
  - Eliot-Pearson/Tufts Joint Committee, 1963 -- 1964; UA009.010.015.00004 (Box 15)
  - Eptonian (Student Newsletter), 1957 -- 1965; UA009.010.015.00005 (Box 15)
  - Exploration of possible affiliation with other schools, 1963; UA009.010.015.00006 (Box 15)
  - Federal Emergency Nursery School, 1934; UA009.010.015.00007 (Box 15)
  - Federal Emergency Nursery School, 1934 -- 1935; UA009.010.015.00008 (Box 15)
  - Foundations, 1961 -- 1962; UA009.010.015.00009 (Box 15)
  - Fundraising, 1926 -- 1949; UA009.010.015.00010 (Box 15)
  - Fundraising, Annual Appeal, 1951 -- 1967; UA009.010.015.00011 (Box 15)
  - Fundraising campaign reports, 1961 -- 1964; UA009.010.015.00012 (Box 15)
  - Fundraising events, 1957 -- 1965; UA009.010.015.00013 (Box 15)
  - Fundraising, special gifts, 1937 -- 1964; UA009.010.015.00014 (Box 15)
  - Grade reports, UA009.010.015.00015 (Box 15)
  - Historical notes and clippings, 1932 -- 1946; UA009.010.015.00016 (Box 15)
  - International committee, 1953 -- 1956; UA009.010.016.00001 (Box 16)
  - International students, 1953 -- 1957; UA009.010.016.00002 (Box 16)
  - Investment committee, 1941 -- 1955; UA009.010.016.00003 (Box 16)
  - Laboratory school, 1940 -- 1942; UA009.010.016.00004 (Box 16)
  - Land grant from Tufts, 1960 -- 1962; UA009.010.016.00005 (Box 16)
  - Long-range planning committee, 1952; UA009.010.016.00006 (Box 16)
  - Merger, 1964; UA009.010.016.00007 (Box 16)
  - Merger, 1964; UA009.010.016.00008 (Box 16)
  - New England School Development Council, 1960 -- 1963; UA009.010.016.00009 (Box 16)
  - Nursery school, 1941 -- 1942; UA009.010.016.00010 (Box 16)
  - Nursery school, 1960 -- 1963; UA009.010.016.00011 (Box 16)
  - Orientation program, 1954 -- 1961; UA009.010.016.00012 (Box 16)
  - Personnel practices committee, 1940 -- 1960; UA009.010.016.00013 (Box 16)
  - Policy on certificates and diplomas, 1944 -- 1955; UA009.010.016.00014 (Box 16)
  - Press releases, 1948 -- 1957; UA009.010.016.00015 (Box 16)
  - Psychology class (Ruggles St.), 1948; UA009.010.016.00016 (Box 16)
  - Project Linc, report, 1977; UA009.010.017.00001 (Box 17)
  - Publicity committee, 1957; UA009.010.017.00002 (Box 17)
  - Public relations, 1932 -- 1949; UA009.010.017.00003 (Box 17)
  - Public relations, 1935 -- 1979; UA009.010.017.00004 (Box 17)
  - Public relations, 1937 -- 1957; UA009.010.017.00005 (Box 17)
  - Public relations, 1950 -- 1959; UA009.010.017.00006 (Box 17)
  - Questionnaires, 1939 -- 1960; UA009.010.017.00007 (Box 17)
  - Radio: Children's Circle, UA009.010.017.00008 (Box 17)
  - Reciprocal programs, 1938 -- 1956; UA009.010.017.00009 (Box 17)
  - Renaming Day, 1955; UA009.010.017.00010 (Box 17)
  - Robb, Elda, 1955; UA009.010.017.00011 (Box 17)
  - Scholarships, 1934 -- 1944; UA009.010.018.00001 (Box 18)
  - Scholarships, 1954 -- 1963; UA009.010.018.00002 (Box 18)
  - State certification, 1933 -- 1954; UA009.010.018.00003 (Box 18)
  - Stearns Village, 1944 -- 1961; UA009.010.018.00004 (Box 18)
  - Stearns Village, 1952 -- 1960; UA009.010.018.00005 (Box 18)
  - Student Council, 1947 -- 1962; UA009.010.018.00006 (Box 18)
  - Student Government, 1945 -- 1962; UA009.010.018.00007 (Box 18)
  - Student Handbook, 1954 -- 1956; UA009.010.018.00008 (Box 18)
  - Student lists, 1957 -- 1961; UA009.010.018.00009 (Box 18)
  - Student: General, 1939 -- 1958; UA009.010.018.00010 (Box 18)
  - Teacher Preparation Program, report (1 of 2), 1981; UA009.010.018.00011 (Box 18)
  - Teacher Preparation Program, report (2 of 2), 1981; UA009.010.019.00001 (Box 19)
  - Television, 1954 -- 1955; UA009.010.019.00002 (Box 19)
  - Transfer students, 1954 -- 1955; UA009.010.019.00003 (Box 19)
  - U.S. National Committee for Childhood Education, 1956 -- 1958; UA009.010.019.00004 (Box 19)
  - White House Conference on Children and Youth, 1951 -- 1961; UA009.010.019.00005 (Box 19)
  - Record: Student Council Notes, 1954 -- 1964; UA009.010.020.00001 (Box 20)
  - Administration, 1957 -- 1960; UA009.010.021.00001 (Box 21)
  - Dormitories, 1957 -- 1963; UA009.010.021.00002 (Box 21)
  - Dormitory Resident Directors, 1956 -- 1958; UA009.010.021.00003 (Box 21)
  - Affiliations with Tufts, 1950 -- 1964; UA009.010.021.00004 (Box 21)
  - Worcester Tornado Project, 1953; UA009.010.021.00005 (Box 21)
  - Counsel correspondence, 1947 -- 1953; UA009.010.021.00006 (Box 21)
  - Treasurer correspondence, 1933 -- 1946; UA009.010.021.00007 (Box 21)
  - Histories and studies, 1957; UA009.010.021.00008 (Box 21)
  - Histories and studies, 1949 -- 1951; UA009.010.021.00009 (Box 21)
- Audiovisual materials, 1920 -- 2011; 1926 -- 1980; UA009.011; 3.7 Linear Feet; 119 Digital Object(s)
  This series includes photographs, slides, and videocassettes documenting the classroom activities of the Eliot-Pearson Department of Child Development from its start as the Ruggles Street Nursery to its current incarnation. The majority of the photographs depict students working in the nursery school or in the classroom. The majority of the photographs are labeled as to which year they were taken but few have any people identified. Some of the photographs are cross-listed with the University Image collection. Also in the collection are public relation scrapbooks which contain newspaper clippings referencing the school. Folders are arranged chronologically. An attempt has been made to keep similar forms of media together.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Photographs, 1943; UA009.011.012.00001 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, groundbreaking [1 of 2], 1962; UA009.011.012.00002 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, groundbreaking [2 of 2], 1962; UA009.011.012.00003 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, [1 of 4], 1962 -- 1964; UA009.011.012.00004 (Box 12)
    Includes negatives.
  - Photographs, [2 of 4], 1962 -- 1964; UA009.011.012.00005 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, [3 of 4], 1962 -- 1964; UA009.011.012.00006 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, [4 of 4], 1962 -- 1964; UA009.011.012.00007 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1967; UA009.011.012.00008 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1974; UA009.011.012.00009 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1974 -- 1983; UA009.011.012.00010 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, Seminar day, 1977; UA009.011.012.00011 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1977; UA009.011.012.00012 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1978; UA009.011.012.00013 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1978; UA009.011.012.00014 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1979; UA009.011.012.00015 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1979; UA009.011.012.00017 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1981; UA009.011.012.00018 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1982; UA009.011.012.00019 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1985; UA009.011.012.00020 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1990; UA009.011.012.00021 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1997; UA009.011.012.00022 (Box 12)
    Includes negatives
  - Photographs, 1998; UA009.011.012.00023 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1998; UA009.011.012.00024 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, festschrift for Sylvia Feinburg, 1999; UA009.011.012.00025 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, retirement celebration for Charna Levine and Sylvia Feinburg [1 of 2], 1999; UA009.011.012.00026 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, retirement celebration for Charna Levine and Sylvia Feinburg [2 of 2], 1999; UA009.011.012.00027 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 2000; UA009.011.012.00028 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, graduation brunch, 2001; UA009.011.012.00029 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 2001; UA009.011.012.00030 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 2001; UA009.011.012.00031 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 2001; UA009.011.012.00032 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 2001; UA009.011.012.00033 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, Bergstrom chair, 2002; UA009.011.012.00034 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 2006; UA009.011.012.00035 (Box 12)
  - Photographs, 1995; UA009.011.012.00036 (Box 12)
    This date is approximate. Includes negatives.
  - Photographs, 1995; UA009.011.012.00037 (Box 12)
  - Slides, 1958 -- 1959; UA009.011.012.00038 (Box 12)
  - Slides, 1971; UA009.011.012.00039 (Box 12)
  - Slides, dedication day curriculum lab, 1975; UA009.011.012.00040 (Box 12)
  - Slides, practicum seminars, 1977; UA009.011.012.00041 (Box 12)
  - Slides, 1977; UA009.011.012.00042 (Box 12)
  - Slides, 1977; UA009.011.012.00043 (Box 12)
  - Slides, 1977; UA009.011.012.00044 (Box 12)
  - Slides, 1977; UA009.011.012.00045 (Box 12)
  - Slides, 1977; UA009.011.012.00046 (Box 12)
  - Lantern slides, 1950; UA009.011.012.00047 (Box 12)
    This box contains 11 lantern slides as well as the original box the slides were housed inside.
  - Videocassette, Lerner installation Lerner, Cummings, and first half of panel discussion, 2000 -- 2004; UA009.011.012.00048 (Box 12)
    videocassette
  - Videocassette, Lerner installation cont. second half of panel discussion, 2000 -- 2004; UA009.011.012.00049 (Box 12)
  - Videocassette, Rich Lerner installation Lerner address, 2000 -- 2004; UA009.011.012.00050 (Box 12)
  - Videocassette, Rich Lerner installation Bergstrom chair, Lerner address, 2000 -- 2004; UA009.011.012.00051 (Box 12)
  - Videocassette, Rick Little 'Globalization of children and youth', 2000 -- 2011; UA009.011.012.00052 (Box 12)
  - Promotional negatives for UNICEF, 1985; UA009.011.012.00053 (Box 12)
  - Manning courtyard landscape plans, 1989 -- 1990; UA009.011.012.00054 (Box 12)
  - Eliot Pearson Child Study Center courtyard garden planting plan, 1990; UA009.011.012.00055 (Box Large Map Case 1 Drawer 5)
  - Public relations, newsclipping scrapbook, 1961 -- 1962; UA009.011.013.00001 (Box 13)
  - Public relations, newsclipping scrapbook, 1970; UA009.011.013.00002 (Box 13)
  - Public Relations, newsclipping scrapbooks, 1920 -- 1951; UA009.011.021.00001 (Box 21)
  - Public Relations, newsclipping scrapbooks, 1930 -- 1955; UA009.011.022.00001 (Box 22)
  - Photos, 1926 -- 1940; UA009.011.028.00001 (Box 28)
  - Photos, 1955 -- 1957; UA009.011.028.00002 (Box 28)
  - Photos, 1961 -- 1980; UA009.011.028.00003 (Box 28)
  - Groundbreaking ceremony of Eliot-Pearson center, 1962-04-28; UA009.011.029.00001; Lenscraft Photos, INC. (Box 29)
    Eliot, Abigail A.; Eliot-Pearson Children's School
  - Groundbreaking ceremony for Eliot-Pearson Center, man with shovel, 1962-04-28; UA009.011.029.00002; Lenscraft Photos, INC. (Box 29)
  - Smiling girl, UA009.011.029.00003; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
    copyright 2000
    Eliot-Pearson Children's School
  - Two boys coloring, UA009.011.029.00004; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
  - Girl reading, UA009.011.029.00005; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
  - Girl with paint, UA009.011.029.00006; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
  - Boy and girl painting, UA009.011.029.00007; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
  - Two girls and teacher, UA009.011.029.00008; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
  - Boy writing, UA009.011.029.00009; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
  - Girl, UA009.011.029.00010; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
    copy right 2000
  - Two children playing at table, 2000; UA009.011.029.00016; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
    Children; People; Eliot-Pearson Children's School
  - Child drawing, 2000; UA009.011.029.00017; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
  - Two children observe something unknown, 2000; UA009.011.029.00018; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
  - Three children playing at table, 2000; UA009.011.029.00019; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
  - Boy standing next to easel, 2000; UA009.011.029.00020; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
  - Child and Tufts student, 2000; UA009.011.029.00021; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
    Children; People; Students; Eliot-Pearson Children's School
  - Children playing with sandbox, 2000; UA009.011.029.00022; Morelli, Mark (Box 29)
  - Eliot-Pearson Children's School, 1960; UA009.011.029.00023 (Box 29)
    This date is approximate
    Buildings; Eliot-Pearson Children's School
  - Children sitting outside Cambridge Nursery School or Ruggles Street Demonstration School, 1926; UA009.011.DO.00121 (Box Shared 26)
    People; Students; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; Eliot-Pearson Dept. of Child Development
  - Student and teacher painting inside Eliot Pearson School, 1957; UA009.011.DO.00122 (Box Shared 27)
    People; Students; Eliot Pearson Department of Child Development, records; Eliot-Pearson Children's School
  - Student playing at sandbox inside Eliot-Pearson School, 1965; UA009.011.DO.00123 (Box Shared 27)
  - Ruggles St. Nursery School, 1955; UA009.011.DO.02036 (Box Shared 28)
    Ruggles Street School
  - Ruggles Street Nursery School, 1955; UA009.011.DO.02037 (Box Shared 28)
  - Ruggles St. Nursery School, 1955; UA009.011.DO.02038 (Box Shared 28)
  - Nursery School, Purdue University, Miss Laura Partch in charge, 1950; UA009.011.DO.02039 (Box Shared 29)
    Schools
  - Miss Gretch showing Miss Chandler materials used in the kindergarten for science experience., 1959; UA009.011.DO.02040; Stacks, Herbert J. (Box Shared 30)
    Child Development; Chandler, Martha H.; Gretsch, Miss Ellen
  - Children Playing, 1950; UA009.011.DO.02041 (Box Shared 30)
    8x10
    Child Development
  - Clark Hill School, children playing tea, 1955; UA009.011.DO.02042 (Box Shared 30)
  - The Clark Hill Nursery School, 1955; UA009.011.DO.02043 (Box Shared 30)
  - Children at play, 1952; UA009.011.DO.02044; Duette (Box Shared 30)
  - Teachers at play, 1955; UA009.011.DO.02045; Zilinsky, Anthony (Box Shared 30)
  - Children at play, 1955; UA009.011.DO.02046 (Box Shared 30)
  - Nursery training school student at Plymouth Church Nursery School, 1955; UA009.011.DO.02047; Bartlett Sisters (Box Shared 30)
  - Children at play, UA009.011.DO.02048; Duette (Box Shared 30)
  - Children at Play, UA009.011.DO.02049; Duette (Box Shared 30)
  - Celebration of 25th anniversary of Nursery Training School, 1947-01-24; UA009.011.DO.02050; Lenscraft Photos, INC. (Box Shared 30)
    Child Development; Pearson, Mrs. Henry Greenleaf; Hymes, James L.; Eliot, Abigail A.
  - Mrs. Sexton, Miss Chandler, Claire Merrill and Miss Spaulding, 1955; UA009.011.DO.02051 (Box Shared 29)
  - Preparing for Commencement, 1953; UA009.011.DO.02052; Duette (Box Shared 30)
  - President Wessell and Mrs. Davies at commencement, 1955; UA009.011.DO.02053; Duette (Box Shared 30)
    Child Development; Commencement; Wessell, Nils Yngve
  - Forough Imami and Miss Cockrey, 1954; UA009.011.DO.02054; Duette (Box Shared 30)
  - Miss Katherine J. Jones, 1955-10; UA009.011.DO.02055; Keller of Belmont (Box Shared 30)
  - Miss Margaret Thatcher, renaming ceremony, 1955-10; UA009.011.DO.02056; Keller of Belmont (Box Shared 30)
  - Dr. Elda Robb recieving citation and Honorary Alumna, 1955; UA009.011.DO.02057; Duette (Box Shared 30)
    From left to right: Miss Cockrell, Dean Kelley, Dr. Elba Robb, Mrs. Davies, Miss Eliot, President Wessell.
    Child Development; Kelley, Richard A.; Eliot, Abigail A.; Wessell, Nils Yngve
  - Former Presidents of Board of Managers of Nursery Training School, 1955-10; UA009.011.DO.02058; Keller, Robert J. (Box Shared 30)
    From left to right: Mrs. Schell, Mrs. Davies, Mrs. Swaim, and Mrs. Goodale.
  - Clark Hill Nursery School [now Eliot Pearson], 1950; UA009.011.DO.02059 (Box Shared 31)
    Currently Eliot-Pearson
  - Women cooking, 1950; UA009.011.DO.02060 (Box Shared 31)
    Miss Helen McDowell [Nutritionist], Miss Leslie Wood, and Betty Werner.
  - Mrs. Helen P. Wiley testing pupil for intelligence and achievement, 1942; UA009.011.DO.02061; Keller, Robert J. (Box Shared 31)
    Mrs. Helen P. Wiley, Directory of Child Study and Research at the Nursery Training School of Boston, rates a Ruggles Street Nursery School pupil for intelligence and achievement. Both schools are celebrating their 20th anniversary this month.
    Child Development; Wiley, Mrs. Helen P.
  - A.A. Eliot's resignation party, 1952; UA009.011.DO.02062 (Box Shared 31)
    Child Development; Eliot, Abigail A.
  - Miscellaneous Birthday Party, 1942-08-02; UA009.011.DO.02063; Keller, Robert J. (Box Shared 31)
  - Children having snack time, 1948-08-11; UA009.011.DO.02064; Keller, Robert J. (Box Shared 31)
  - Rachel McMillan Training College, 1931; UA009.011.DO.02065 (Box Shared 29)
    Postcard with writing on back
  - Rachel Mcmillan Training College, interior, 1931; UA009.011.DO.02066 (Box Shared 29)
    Postcard with writing on the back.
  - From Mrs. John Freeman, 1952-06; UA009.011.DO.02067 (Box Shared 29)
  - Miss Abilgail A. Eliot, 1950; UA009.011.DO.02068 (Box Shared 31)
  - Dr. Abigail A. Eliot and Mrs. Henry Greenleaf Pearson, 1955-10; UA009.011.DO.02069; Keller of Belmont (Box Shared 31)
    Child Development; Eliot, Abigail A.; Pearson, Mrs. Henry Greenleaf
  - Dr. Abigail A. Eliot, 1952-06; UA009.011.DO.02070 (Box Shared 29)
  - Miss Eliot and Mrs. Pearson, 1955-10; UA009.011.DO.02071; Keller of Belmont (Box Shared 31)
  - D. Louise Cockrell, 1955; UA009.011.DO.02072 (Box Shared 29)
  - On the way to Eliot resignation party, 1952-06; UA009.011.DO.02073 (Box Shared 29)
  - Nursery School, Miss Laura Partch in charge, 1940; UA009.011.DO.02074 (Box Shared 29)
  - Rachel McMillan Training College, interior view, 1931; UA009.011.DO.02075 (Box Shared 29)
    Post card with writing on the back
  - Nursery Training School of Boston, 1940; UA009.011.DO.02076; Keller, Robert J. (Box Shared 31)
  - A. A. Eliot, resignation party, 1952; UA009.011.DO.02077 (Box Shared 31)
  - A. A. Eliot resignation party, 1952-09-22; UA009.011.DO.02078 (Box Shared 31)
  - A. A. Eliot resignation party, 1952; UA009.011.DO.02079 (Box Shared 31)
  - Renaming Ceremony, 1955-10; UA009.011.DO.02081 (Box Shared 31)
  - A. A. Eliot and Mrs. Peterson [First Student at NTS], 1952; UA009.011.DO.02082 (Box Shared 31)
    Child Development; Eliot, Abigail A.; Peterson, Mrs.
  - Renaming Ceremony, [Miss Eliot, Miss Cockrell, Mrs. Davies, Mrs. Peterson], 1955-10; UA009.011.DO.02083 (Box Shared 31)
    Miss Eliot, Miss Cockrell, Mrs. Davies, and Mrs. Pearson.
  - 25th anniversary of Nursery Training School of Boston, 1947-01-24; UA009.011.DO.02084; Lenscraft Photos, INC. (Box Shared 31)
    Child Development; Hymes, James L.; Eliot, Abigail A.
  - Children at Brooks School in Concord, 1956; UA009.011.DO.02085; Duette (Box Shared 31)
  - Nursery Training School, 1953; UA009.011.DO.02086; Duette (Box Shared 31)
  - Three year old Kirsten Aaroe of Medford rides the hobby horse in the school's outdoor play yard., 1953; UA009.011.DO.02087; Duette (Box Shared 31)
  - The Clark Hill Nursery School, 1940; UA009.011.DO.02088 (Box Shared 31)
  - Ruggles St. Nursery School, 1950; UA009.011.DO.02089; Keller, Robert J. (Box Shared 31)
  - Stearns Village Nursery School George R. Gordon pictured], 1960-11-01; UA009.011.DO.02090; Carr, Edward F. (Box Shared 31)
    George R. Gordon 4.5 years old